Oisin Tohak

Junior Fullstack Developer

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, PYTHON

Portfolio: www.oisintohak.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oisintohak/

Github: https://github.com/oisintohak

Phone: +91 7590 874 682 Email: mail@oisintohak.com

I'm an accomplished Fullstack developer with 8+ years working in catering during which I oversaw a 20% increase in production and sales. Equally comfortable working independently and within a sprint-based agile team environment. A skilled problem-solver and constant learner, I pride myself on delivering a first-rate user experience with every project.

SKILLS

<u>Frontend</u>	<u>Backend</u>	<u>Transferable</u>
HTML 5	Python	Problem Solving
CSS 3	Flask	Adaptability

JavaScript Django Communication

EXPERIENCE

SQL

Atomic, Remote -Web Developer Internship (React.js)

React JS

JULY 2021 - PRESENT

Atomic.dev is building a low-code platform that will drastically reduce development time. I'm involved in developing the frontend of this platform. My duties include:

- Maintain clear and consistent communication with team members to ensure code consistency.
- Translating Figma designs into high quality code.
- Develop user-facing features using React, Redux and styled-components.
- Sending requests to the platform API and handling response data.
- Develop components to handle and process user input.

Govindas, Galway Ireland - Catering

2012 - 2014, 2015 - 2021

I was involved in all aspects of running a successful catering business. I was the sole operator of this business for extended periods. Duties included:

- Preparing a selection of Indian vegetarian dishes to serve upwards of 400 customers per day.
- Training new staff to correctly follow the set routine and ensure that team members operate efficiently with each other.
- Adhering to health and safety requirements, recording consistent temperature checks and sanitation.

Oxfam, Dublin Ireland - Fundraiser

2014

I worked with a team as a direct dialogue, door-to-door fundraiser. My duties included:

- Informing people about our various campaigns and humanitarian efforts.
- Inspiring people to commit to a scheduled regular donation.
- Representing the business and ensuring that all encounters with the public left a positive impression.

EDUCATION

Code Institute (Ireland/Remote) - Diploma in Software Development

SEPT 2020 - PRESENT

This is a fully remote course and it is the only University Credit-Rated bootcamp in Europe. Being on a remote course has given me the skillset to communicate and collaborate effectively within a distributed team and I have participated in 2 student hackathons during this course. It is divided into 4 modules and corresponding projects:

- User Centric Frontend Development:
 - o HTML5 & CSS3
 - Mobile-first and responsive design.
 - Project Planning and developing from user stories.
 - User Experience
- Interactive Frontend Development
 - Javascript (ES6 & jQuery)
 - Interacting with APIs
 - Responding to user input
- Data Centric Development
 - Python
 - Flask Framework
 - o SOL
 - o MongoDB
- Full Stack Frameworks
 - Django Framework
 - PostgreSQL
 - Ecommerce Development & Payment Processing

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- As I like to keep up to date with emerging technologies and trends in the industry I read a lot of tech-related articles on sites like Medium and Wired. I also subscribe to development related podcasts such as Syntax.fm and CodeNewbie.
- I've been playing drums and percussion for as long as I can remember and I seize any opportunity to play with other musicians in styles ranging from Metal to Funk to Indian classical music.